Professional Title

I am a team player dedicated to personal growth and development, community focused and of strong personal value. Ensuring a down-to-earth approach to project management with significant experience in Web Development.



anandshyamak210198@gmail.com (+91)-9110916390
Ranchi, Jharkhand, India linkedin.com/in/shyamak-anand/twitter.com/AnandShyamak facebook.com/shyamak.anand medium.com/@anandshyamak210198

EMPLOYMENT

Front-End Developer Intern

HighRadius Corporation

Nov 2020 - Present

- Working as a Front-end developer with a specialization in HTML, CSS, JS and React.
- Identified web-based user interactions and developed a highly responsive user interface components via React concepts.
- Developed a Call-Workboard Autonomous Application using React and Material-UI concepts.
- Developed an Invoice Screen Application and Inventory Management System using React and flex-box concepts.

Software Intern Infinity Ltd, Ranchi May 2019 - June 2019

- Developed an interest in writing a well designed, testable, efficient code by using best software development practices.
- Created a web-based user interface by using standard HTML/CSS and JavaScript practices.
- Integrated data from various back-end services and databases.

Student Trainee BSNL May 2018 - June 2018

- Vocational training in Data Communication and Networking.
- Developed an understanding and exposure in telecommunication technologies.
- Worked on area such as IP, Networking and Cyber Security.
- Got to know about the Broadband technology, Digital Switching Systems, Digital Transmission Systems & Telecom Support Infrastructure.

Languages and Technologies

- Programming Languages HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, C++
- Operating System Linux, Windows, Ubuntu
- Database MongoDB, MySQL, Apache
- Frameworks React JS, Redux, Bootstrap, Material-UI, Rest API, Node JS, Visual Studio Code,
- Eclipse Others Blockchain Fundamentals, FL Studio

EDUCATION

Bhubaneswar, India

Kalinga Institute of Industrial Technology

June 2017 - Present

- B.Tech in Information Technology. CGPA: 8.2
- Main coursework: Data Structures, Design and Analysis of Algorithms, Computer Architecture, Web Technology,
 Database Management System, Operating Systems, Software Engineering & Computer Networking.

B.TECH - PROJECT

- Food Traceability & Supply Chain Management System through Blockchain.
- Inventory & Invoice Management Autonomous System using Full Stack development.
- Face Recognition System using React JS.

ACHIEVEMENTS AND RESPONSIBILITIES

- Selected as the Campus Ambassador for Asia's Largest Cultural Festival, Mood Indigo, IIT Bombay.
- Coordinator of K KUBE, one of the cultural society in KIIT.
- Performed in various musical events and competitions across India.
- Secured a runner up position in Spring Fest '19.
- Finalist in Asia's Largest Cultural Fest, IIT Bombay.